vcf2report — turn a raw exome VCF into
an auditable ACMG report. Offline. In seconds.
One command: point Claude at a VCF
and the patient's phenotype (HPO terms).
An app appears inside Claude:
a per-sample session and a command panel.
Live phases — Local = the deterministic engine
on your machine · Claude = phenotype→HPO + narrative.
24,801 variants → 2 candidates,
fully offline (~3 seconds).
The result: a draft laudo (report).
SCN1A — Pathogenic (primary) ·
RB1 — Pathogenic (secondary, ACMG SF actionable).
Not a black box: every ACMG criterion is shown.
PVS1 + PM2 + PP4 + PP5 → Pathogenic —
each with its source and date.
engine = decided deterministically ·
model = left for expert review.
Real databases, all local:
gnomAD v4.1 · full ClinVar · AlphaMissense.
The VCF never leaves the machine.
Same engine, any phenotype:
Marfan, colorectal, renal, retinoblastoma…
AlphaMissense recovers a pathogenic missense:
PAX6 → Likely Pathogenic (0.9999) — VUS without it.
Does it actually work? 200 real ClinVar variants —
ClinVar withheld from the engine (non-circular).
0 pathogenic-vs-benign flips ·
100% precision when it commits.
At scale: 5,335 real cases · 1,067 / 1,067
known ClinVar-pathogenic surfaced — 0 missed.
246 automated tests passing ·
everything reproducible offline.
Built with Claude Code —
hardened by multi-agent adversarial review.
Draft aid, not a diagnostic device.
github.com/gbbarra/vcf2report